We'll start by drawing a simple block.
Turn on Area mode for easier areas.
Darken the current side, then set other sides to shades of the new color.
Long press on a cube side to open a color selector.
Select all and copy to clipboard. Clipboard has full history of previous items copied or cut.
Unselect all.
Sample color from existing tile, then darken.
Paste tower tiles copied previously.
Change erase mode with long press.
Saving is automatic; the only time action is needed is to change the name.
Start a new scene for the background.
Select all and copy to this scene's clipboard.
Save this scene as Grass then switch back to the original scene.
A long press on the Paste button brings up a list with previous items copied in this scene and a dialog option to select from other scenes' clipboards.
We're now going to select and then paste an item from the Grass scene's clipboard.
Note that each scene is auto-saved when closed.
Each scene has persistent undo & redo stacks; at any time, you can rewind to an earlier state. You can then save, and redo the actions later on if required.
The undo/redo facility also provides for branching, so you can undo some work, try a new approach, and then revert to the original version, all within the application.
Scenes can be exported to PNG or JPEG files, and common image formats can be imported to any of the 3 planes.
We'll draw a simple shape and export it.
Exports can be done in various predefined page sizes for printing or a custom size can be specified, as here.
Now we'll import the image file we just created.
Thanks for watching.